# **FAHRU ROJAK**

Bandung, Jawa Barat (40625)

**Phone:** +62 82121212426 | **E-mail:** gfahru5@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/fahrurojak/ | Portofolio: https://tinyurl.com/4mychead

#### **SUMMARY**

a sixth-semester Informatics Engineering student with a passion for Frontend Development and Data Analytics. In addition to proficiency in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, I also have experience mini project using the PHP, Laravel, ReactJS framework for web application development. In Data Analytics, I have the ability to use Python for data analysis and data visualization with Looker Studio. Driven by a desire to continuously learn and grow, I actively seek opportunities to contribute to software development and data-driven projects. My technical skills and enthusiasm for learning make me confident that I can tackle challenges and excel in the professional world.

#### **EDUCATION**

Universitas Nurtanio - Bandung, Indonesia

S1 Informatics Engineering GPA: 3.16/4.0 in 5<sup>th</sup> Semester

**EXPERIENCE** 

# Studi Independen Kampus Merdeka x RevoU

Aug. 2023 – Dec. 2023

Sep. 2021 – Present

Data Analytics & Software Engineering

- Participated as mentee in cycle 1 and cycle 2, for two months on intro to software engineering using HTML, CSS and Javascript (Node.js). and for two months on intro to data analytics using SQL, Python, Spreadsheet, for Data Cleaning and Visualization using Looker Studio.
- Led a team of 6 in managing project progress using a custom-built spreadsheet, significantly enhancing team communication and mentor, and ensuring timely project completion.
- Collaborated with team on the final project (capstone project) with a case study of a health service application called Chatdoc as a Frontend with Final score 87, and New York City Sales Property case study as a Visualization with Final score 95.

## VSGA Digitalent Scholarship x Kominfo

Apr. 2023 – May. 2023

Junior Web Developer

- Participated in a two month online training program and gained experience in using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to build responsive and attractive user interfaces.
- Utilized PHP, MySQL to develop database-driven web applications, ensuring efficient data management.

# **ORGANIZATION EXPERIENCES**

## **Internet Of Things (IoT)**

Nov. 2021 – Present

Committee

• Participated in a meeting on IoT device preparation, instructing participants in Arduino Uno coding sessions and providing comprehensive materials to ensure understanding.

**Multimedia** Nov. 2021 – Agu. 2022

Member

• Develop proficiency in photo and video editing software like Adobe Photoshop, Premiere Pro, along with additional tools.

#### **ADDITIONAL INFORMATION**

**Certificate :** Revou Data Analytics & Software Engineering | VSGA Digitalent Scholarship Junior Web Developer | Dicoding x DBS Bank | Mari Belajar Scholarship Data Analyst & AI

- Hard Skill: Frontend Development: HTML, CSS, PHP, JavaScript, Laravel, React, Bootstrap | Data Analytics: Proficient in Python, Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, and Seaborn and visualization. | Other: Git
- Language: Bahasa Indonesia (Native), English (Intermediate).